<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Ding Yanran]]></title>
  <link href="http://github-firefly.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://github-firefly.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-19T21:15:28+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://github-firefly.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ding Yanran]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexapod Robot]]></title>
    <link href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/hexapod-robot/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-19T15:00:47+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/hexapod-robot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Hexapod Robot</h3>

<p>Inspired by the prosperity and variety of the contemporary field of hexapod robot, our group had decided to make one that can move forward and backward. There are many types of hexapod robots and we decided to start with the simplest, therefore a design which is based on four-link mechanism was incorporated in our final design.</p>

<p>We started this project from scratch. After doing much researching, we got to know more about the state of art and in the end we came up with a design filled with our teammates’ ingenuity and creativity. Based on the design, we started the assembly. Our research method is mainly hands-on, which means we find a problem when we are tinkering and come up with a solution. The main ways of manufacturing the parts involves lathe turning, drilling, metal bending, sawing, mechanical cutting, laser cutting, soldering, adhesive and mechanical fastenings including screws and bolts, clamp spring restraining. Due to the fact that we were lack of engineering experiences and knowledge, we ran into many difficulties. Thanks to the teachers in the engineering training center, we solved all the problems successfully despite all the stumbles during the process.</p>

<p>In the end, our team had manufactured a hexapod that can move forward and backward, and turn left or right. The basic structure of the robot consists of two parts: mechanical part and electrical part. The mechanical part involves the legs, the body and the gears; the electrical part includes the motors, the circuit and the battery. Together, they bring the hexapod robot into life.</p>

<p>The four-link mechanism makes it possible for this robot to move with six legs driven by only two motors. Compared to other kinds of hexapod robots, this robot is definitely primitive, yet there is beauty lies in its simplicity.</p>

<p><strong>Keywords</strong>: hexapod robot, four-link mechanism, machining process technology</p>

<p><a href="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn062/20141019/1455/original_X818_2d7f00020651125d.jpg">[Pic]Overall View of Hexapod Robot</a></p>

<p><a href="http://fmn.xnpic.com/fmn056/20141019/1455/original_Zs1D_6ea700008d4b1190.jpg">[Pic]Side View of Hexapod</a></p>

<p><a href="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn060/20141019/1455/original_GFwx_15b00000f2f1118c.jpg">[Pic]Top View of Hexapod</a></p>

<p><a href="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn060/20141019/1455/original_Bfku_69620002951e125f.jpg">[Pic]Bottom View of Hexapod</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vision Based Quadcopter]]></title>
    <link href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/vision-based-quadcopter/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-19T13:37:27+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/vision-based-quadcopter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>The Research of Vision System Based Autonomous Quadrotor Cruise</h3>

<h4>Introduction</h4>

<p>Quadcopters have been utilized in many fields and one of them is power grid cruise.
The objective of this project is to develop a mechanical arm that can automatically hold
on to the power cable with visual feedback from the camera mounted on the top of the quad.
Solidworks was used in designing and simulating motion of the mechanical arms and Python
script was used together with OpenCV extension in annalyzing visual signals and motion control.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Mechanical Design</p>

<p> <a href="http://fmn.rrfmn.com/fmn061/20141019/1415/original_HcFj_13f100024c321191.jpg">[Pic]Power Cable Fixture Design</a></p>

<p> <a href="http://fmn.rrimg.com/fmn065/20141019/1415/original_qPRH_4c5100024e61118f.jpg">[Pic]Four-bar Linkage Mechanism of Mechanical Arm</a></p>

<p> <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/486tnedakkllp7e/IMG_0136.MOV?dl=0">[Video]Test of Mechanical Arm</a></p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plannar Motor]]></title>
    <link href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/planar-motor/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-19T12:46:33+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/planar-motor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Large-stroke Piezo-actuated Plannar Motor for Nanopositioning Application</h3>

<h4><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/5lgah8mau09zklo/FIG1%20Final.tif?dl=0">Plannar Motor Configuration</a></h4>

<h3>Abstract</h3>

<p>This paper presents a large-stroke piezo-actuated planar motor for nano-positioning
applications. The planar motor uses an air bearing with vacuum preload to reduce
friction. Four piezo legs located at each corner of the mover can perform three
operation modes to drive the planar motor, the skiing mode, the stepping mode,
and the tilting mode. The skiing mode is a high-speed actuation mode. The stepping
mode provides high-resolution trajectory tracking capability. The tilting mode allows
for fine adjustment of the stage in its final position with the highest resolution.
These three operation modes have different positioning advantages and can be combined
to achieve both a high positioning speed and a high positioning resolution. This
planar motor has large stroke that is only limited by the base size and large
rotation range up to 360°. Two measurement systems based on flat panel display
are developed to evaluate the motion performance of the planar motor including
motion resolution and trajectory tracking accuracy.</p>

<h3>Keywords</h3>

<p>planar motor, stage, positioning system, piezo, flexure hinge, planar encoder,
semiconductor production</p>

<h4><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/tqdvduwpdb1r9ef/journal%20material.pdf?dl=0">Download PDF</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resume]]></title>
    <link href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/18/personal-information/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-18T22:58:52+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/18/personal-information</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<h3>Basic Information</h3>

<ul>
<li>Name: Ding Yanran</li>
<li>Gender: Male

<ul>
<li>Email: <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#x3a;&#100;&#x69;&#110;&#x67;&#x79;&#97;&#x6e;&#114;&#x61;&#x6e;&#95;&#50;&#48;&#x31;&#49;&#x40;&#x73;&#106;&#x74;&#x75;&#46;&#101;&#100;&#117;&#46;&#99;&#110;">&#100;&#105;&#110;&#103;&#x79;&#x61;&#110;&#114;&#97;&#x6e;&#95;&#x32;&#x30;&#49;&#x31;&#x40;&#x73;&#x6a;&#x74;&#117;&#x2e;&#101;&#100;&#x75;&#x2e;&#x63;&#110;</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3>Education</h3>

<ul>
<li>09/11-08/15(expected) <strong>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</strong> (SJTU)

<ul>
<li>University of Michigan - Shanghai Jiao Tong University Joint Institute (UM - JI)</li>
<li>Mechanical Engineering (B.S.E)</li>
<li>GPA: 3.8/4.0 (overall) 4.0/4.0 (core)</li>
<li>Rank: 1/53</li>
<li>Courses: Mechatronis, Mechanics, Manufacturing, Dynamics,
Thermodynamics, Circuits</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3>Experience</h3>

<p><strong>Research Assistant</strong>, <em>Laboratory for Optical Measurement and Sensing</em>,
  SJTU, Shanghai</p>

<ul>
<li>Worked with a graduate student in developing a piezo-actuated <a href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/planar-motor/"><strong>nano-positioning
planar motor</strong></a>. This planar motor has large linear and angular range
of motion. Position of the planar motor is obtained by a high resolution 2D encoder.</li>
<li>Actualized motion control algorithm for the planar motor in LabVIEW.
Added <em>I</em> controller to the system, limited the deviation in skiing mode within ±1μm.
Acquired experience in PID parameter tuning.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Project Leader</strong>,<em>School of Electronic Information and Electrical Engineering</em>,
SJTU, Shanghai</p>

<ul>
<li>Customized a <a href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/vision-based-quadcopter/"><strong>quadcopter</strong></a> with visual feedback. Designed
and built a mechanical
arm on a quadcoptor that allows it to slide on electric cable for the purpose
of power-efficient cruise.</li>
<li>This project had been elevated to <strong>7th National Innovation Training Plan</strong> for
Undergraduates.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Design Engineer Intern</strong>, <em>Ju Zhi Startup team</em>, SJTU, Shanghai</p>

<ul>
<li>Collaborated with graduate and PhD students in designing an <strong>automatic production
line</strong> of slide switches.</li>
<li>Designed a mechanism to guide and position the metal shell of a slide switch in
mass production. Gained hands-on experience in non-standard mechanism design and
assembly. Familiarity with tolerance and surface roughness choice in metal part
design.</li>
<li>Created an <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/hksriuu9j0yfwke/%E8%81%9A%E6%99%BA%E6%8B%A8%E5%8A%A8%E5%BC%80%E5%85%B3%E5%B1%95%E7%A4%BA.mp4?dl=0"><strong>animation</strong></a> of the production line in the presentation for sponsors.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Project Leader</strong>, <em>Engineering Training Center</em>, SJTU, Shanghai</p>

<ul>
<li>Designed and built a <a href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/hexapod-robot/"><strong>hexapod robot</strong></a> based on four-bar linkage mechanism through several iterations.</li>
<li>Developed independent design ability. Extensive exposure to multiple <strong>manufacturing methods</strong>.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Teaching Assistant</strong>, <em>Joint Institute</em>, SJTU, Shanghai</p>

<ul>
<li>Courses: Chemistry, Dynamics and Vibration, Laboratory I.</li>
<li>Worked with the professor to design and implemented multiple laboratories for 40 students.

<ul>
<li>Held office hour and recitation classes. Employed Socratic Method in facilitating analytical thinking amongst students.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3>Honors and Awards</h3>

<ul>
<li>11/13 National Scholarship for Undergraduates (<strong>top 2%</strong>)

<ul>
<li>Awarded by Ministry of Education of the People’s Republic of China.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>12/13 Academic Excellence Scholarship of Shanghai Jiao Tong University (Second Class)

<ul>
<li>Issued by Shanghai Jiao Tong University.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>05/13 IDC Robocon 2013 YASKAMA Cup SJTU Campus Selecting Competition (Second Place)

<ul>
<li>Funded by YASKAMA, Inc. Japan; issued by SJTU.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>12/12 Academic Excellence Scholarship of Shanghai Jiao Tong University (Third Class)

<ul>
<li>Issued by Shanghai Jiao Tong University.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3>SKILLS</h3>

<ul>
<li>Software: Solidworks, LabVIEW, MATLAB, Mathematica Microsoft office, Python, C/C++, Arduino

<ul>
<li>Language: TOEFL: 108; GRE: 331 (Verbal: 161 Quantitative: 170 Writing: 4.0)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3>Other Links</h3>

<h4>1. <a href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/planar-motor/">planar Motor</a></h4>

<h4>2. <a href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/vision-based-quadcopter/">Vision Based Quadcopter</a></h4>

<h4>3. <a href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/19/hexapod-robot/">Hexapod</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to My Blog!]]></title>
    <link href="http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/13/welcom-to-my-blog/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T22:55:51+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://github-firefly.github.io/blog/2014/10/13/welcom-to-my-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Ding Yanran&rsquo;s Octopress blog!</p>

<p>Special thanks to <em>Ray Zhang</em> for his Technical support.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
